Finding Aid for School of Natural Resources and Environment (University of Michigan) Records 1903-2012.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- General Topical Files, 1913-1990
  - 1928-1990
    - Resource Ecology and Management
      - Faculty Evaluations and Specialization Coordinator Selection, 1988-1989 (Box 53)
    - Resource Policy and Behavior
      - General, 1988/89-1989/90; 2 folders (Box 24)
      - Program Chair Selection, 1988 (Box 53)
        [PR RESTRICTED until July 1, 2018 ]
    - Scholarships, Fellowships, Student Awards, and Financial Aid
      - General, 1948; 1964-1988 (Box 24)
      - Alumni War Memorial Award, 1948-1972 (Box 24)
      - Charles Lathrop Pack Essay Competition, 1975-1988 (Box 24)
      - Clara Carter Higgins Scholarship Fund (The Garden Club of America), 1967-1975 (Box 24)
      - Donald M. Matthews Memorial Award, 1960-1980 (Box 24)
      - The Federated Garden Clubs of Michigan
        - Elsie Cook Scholarship, 1967-1991 (Box 24)
        - Hazel Johnson Scholarship, 1965-1990 (Box 24)
      - Grosse Point Garden Club, 1973-1989 (Box 24)
      - Howard M. Wight Memorial Award, 1947-1964 (Box 24)
      - Jeannine Boukai Award, 1977-1988 (Box 24)
      - Jeffrey Lund Forest Ecology Award, 1982-1984 (Box 24)
      - Joseph L. Sax Fellow Award, 1988 (Box 24)
      - Karl Kidder Memorial Fund, 1971-1989 (Box 24)
      - Mertz-Brown Scholarship, 1974-1989 (Box 24)
      - Mrs. F. Gordon Davis Scholarship, 1965-1986 (Box 24)
      - Samuel Trask Dana Award in Conservation, 1960-1977 (Box 24)
      - Scholarship Committee, 1967-1981 (Box 24)
      - Tinker Foundation, 1979-1984 (Box 24)
      - Woman's National Farm and Garden Association
        - Ann Arbor Branch, 1966-1989 (Box 24)
        - Osage Branch, 1966-1983 (Box 24)
    - Space and Space Committee
      - General
        - 1951-1955 (Box 24)
        - 1964-1968 (Box 24)
        - 1970-1979, 3 folders (Box 24)
        - 1980-1981, 1984 (Box 24)
      - Space Requests, 1974-1975 (Box 24)
    - Specialization Coordinators (Box 25)
      - General, 1984; 1987-1988 (Box 25)
        (includes specialization self-evaluations)
      - Meetings, 1984/85-1987/88; 4 folders (Box 25)
      - New Course Proposals, 1985; 1987-1988 (Box 25)
    - Strategic Planning Retreat
      - General, 1987-1989 (Box 25)
      - Report and Appendix, 1988; 3 folders (Box 25)
    - Students, Graduate, 1988 (Box 25)
    - Undergraduate Committee, 1980-1982; 2 folders (Box 25)
    - Undergraduate Counseling, 1969-1974 (Box 25)
    - Undergraduate Curriculum Committee, 1972 (Box 25)
    - Undergraduate Program
      - General, 1969-1976 (Box 25)
      - Pilot Program, 1971-1973 (Box 25)
      - Undergraduate Program Committee, 1972-1975 (Box 25)
    - US Bureau of Commercial Fisheries Educational Grants, 1965-1966 (Box 26)
    - USDA Forest Service, 1982-1983 (Box 26)
    - University Lands for Teaching and Research, Committee on, 1952 (Box 26)
    - Wildland Management Center
      - General, 1983; 1985 (Box 26)
      - Final Report: Second International Conference on Conservation Biology, 1985 (Box 26)
      - Review, 1986-1987 (Box 26)
    - Women's Network (UM), 1983-1984 (Box 26)
  - 1916-2005
    - Alumni Board of Governors, 1992 (Box 67)
    - Bierbaum, Rosina Ann, 2005-2007; undated (Box 67)
    - Dana Renovation
      - CAD Images, 1998 (Box 67)
      - Kresge Foundation, 1998-1999 (Box 67)
      - Miscellaneous, 1997-2003 (Box 67)
      - Presentation: The Greening of Dana, undated (Box 67)
      - Proposal, 1999 (Box 67)
    - Fellowships
      - Alcoa Foundations Conservation and Sustainability Fellowship Program, 2006 (Box 67)
    - Forest Service
      - Huron National Forest
        - Photographs, 1935-1938 (Box 67)
        - Reports
          - 1937 M-3 Activities on the Huron National Forest, 1938 (Box 67)
          - 1936 M-3 Operations on the Huron National Forest, 1937 (Box 67)
          - Establishment Report and 1935 Progress Report of Jack Pine Cutting Plots on the Huron National Forest, 1936, 1935-1936 (Box 67)
          - Determining Causes of Mortality in Forest Plantations, 1938 (Box 67)
      - Roscommon Forest Fire Experiment Station
        - Miscellaneous, 1930-1947 (Box 67)
        - Photographs Slash Disposal Plots, 1930-1931 (Box 67)
        - Reports
          - 1937 Progress in Management of Jack Pine Studies at Roscommon, 1938 (Box 67)
          - 1938 Progress in Studies of Jack Pine Management at Roscommon, 1939 (Box 67)
          - Forest Planting Studies at Roscommon 1937 Progress, 1938, 1937-1938 (Box 67)
          - Forest Planting Studies at Roscommon 1938 Progress, 1939, 1938-1939 (Box 67)
          - Forest Planting Studies at Roscommon 1939 Progress, 1940, 1939-1940 (Box 67)
        - Work Plan, 1936 (Box 67)
    - Fresh Air Camp, 1949-1961 (Box 68)
      (includes aerial photographs)
    - History Project, undated (Box 68)
    - Marketing Project, 2005; undated (Box 68)
    - Presentations
      - Water-Related Programs, 2006 (Box 68)
    - Presidents Reports, 1964-1980
      - Annual Reports, 1957/58; 1960/61; 1963/64; 1964/65; 1968/69; 1974/75 (Box 68)
      - Proposed Work Plans, 1951/52; 1959/60; 1963/64 (Box 68)
      - Saginaw Forest
        - Carow, John., 80 Years of Pine Plantation Management in Michigan, 1983 (Box 68)
        - Lot Records, 1968-1971 (Box 68)
        - Plantation Measurements, 1916-1960; 11 folders (Box 68)
        - Thinning Experiment, 1914-1924 (Box 69)
      - Stinchfield Woods
        - Murray, Frank., Data on Hardwood Type, 1949 (Box 69)
        - A Guide to Stinchfield Woods, 1952 (Box 69)
        - Hardwood Stands, 1954; 1964 (Box 69)
        - Lot Records, 1965-1980; 2 folders (Box 69)
        - Photographs (Aerial), 1949-1964 (Box 69)
        - Plantation Measurements
          - Block II, Book II, 1931-1960 (Box 69)
          - Conifer, 1978 (Box 69)
          - Hardwood, 1980 (Box 69)
        - Scharf, Richard M., Thinning Time Study, 1956 (Box 69)
        - Stand and Cutting Summary, 1949 (Box 69)
        - Ringwood Forest, 1931; 1953; 3 maps (Folder 1)
        - Saginaw Forest, 1932-1963; undated; 9 maps (Folder 1)
        - Stinchfield Woods, 1936-1964; undated; 14 maps (Folder 1)
        - Other
          - Imp Lake Area, 1962 (Folder 1)
          - Gogebic County
            - Map of the Cedar Swamp Cutting Area, undated (Folder 1)
            - Map of Logging Roads, Sample Plots, & Deer Enclosures, undated (Folder 1)
          - Sharon Hollow Woods -- Proposed Purchase Unit, 1965 (Box 69)
          - Woodlots in the Vicinity of Ann Arbor, Michigan, undated (Box 69)
    - Proposals
      - A Proposal for the Development of an Environmental Education Camp at Camp Hayo-Went-Ha of the State YMCA of Michigan, 1996 (Box 69)
    - Reports
      - Web Site Analysis: Report and Phase II Recommendation, 2006 (Box 69)
    - Strategic Planning Retreat
      - Report, 2005 (Box 69)
    - Students
      - Graduating Student Survey, 2005 (Box 69)
- Budget Materials, 1962-1984
  The Budget Materials series (.7 linear ft.) consists of the working folders relating to the annual budgets from the dean's office. The folders, arranged chronologically, range from 1962 to 1984 and include such materials as memoranda, worksheets, graphs, and reports
  - 1962-1966 (Box 5)
    (Salary Information)
  - 1964-1967 (Box 5)
    (Operating Trends)
  - 1965-1969 (Box 5)
    (Summary)
  - 1971-1974 (Box 5)
    (Internal Procedures)
  - 1976-1977
    - Faculty Salaries (Box 5)
    - General (Box 5)
  - 1977-1978
    - Accounts (Box 5)
    - Salary Program (Box 5)
  - 1978
    - Fall Conference (Box 5)
    - Workshop (Box 5)
  - 1978-1979
    - Faculty Salaries (Box 5)
    - General Fund (Box 5)
    - Hearings (Box 5)
    - Worksheets (Box 5)
  - 1979-1980
    - Priority Fund (Box 5)
    - Program Revision Request (Box 5)
    - Statistical and Analytical Information (Box 5)
  - 1980
    - Reduction Planning (Box 5)
    - Vice President for Academic Affairs (Billy Frye) (Box 5)
  - 1980-1981 (Box 5)
    (one time worksheets)
  - 1980-1982 (Box 5)
    (adjustments)
  - 1981
    - Correspondence (Box 5)
    - Work file (Box 5)
  - 1981-1982
    - Accounts (Box 5)
    - One time money (Box 5)
  - 1982 (Box 5)
    (planning trade offs)
  - 1983-1984 (Box 5)
    (accounts)
  - 1984 (Box 5)
- Committees and Task Forces, 1966-1984; 2006
  The Committees and Task Forces series (1.3 linear feet) includes both academic and administrative committees and task forces from 1966 to 1984 within the School of Natural Resources. Documentation of some committees is limited, but most folders include minutes, membership lists and communications amongst committee members.
  - General (Membership, Charges and Responsibilities), 1977-1983 (Box 5)
  - Academic Opportunity Committee (report: minority affairs), 1972 (Box 5)
  - Alumni Affairs Committee, undated (Box 5)
  - Alumni Visiting Committee, 1980-1981 (Box 5)
  - Biological Station Ad Hoc Committee, 1967 (Box 5)
  - Camp Filibert Roth Committee, 1981-1982 (Box 5)
  - Communications Committee, 1982 (Box 5)
  - Cooperative Schools Committee, 1976-1982 (Box 5)
  - Environmental Resources, Committee on, 1975 (Box 5)
  - Executive Committee and Program Chairman Retreat, 1976 (Box 5)
  - Faculty Code Committee, 1971-1975 (Box 5)
  - Faculty-Student Relations, 1968 (Box 5)
  - Fisheries, Advisory Committee for, 1976-1979 (Box 5)
  - Fishery and Wildlife Review Committee, 1975 (Box 5)
  - Forestry Advisory Council, 1980 (Box 5)
  - Graduate Affairs Committee
    - Memoranda, 1972-1980 (Box 5)
    - Minutes (incomplete run), 1972-1981 (Box 5)
    - Reports, 1978-1983 (Box 5)
  - Further Integration of Landscape Architecture in the School of Natural Resources, Task Group on, 1972 (Box 63)
  - Involvement of Black Students in the SNR, Ad Hoc Committee on, 1970 (Box 63)
  - Minority Affairs Advisory Committee, 1981 (Box 6)
  - Natural Resources 301, Ad Hoc Committee on, 1978 (Box 6)
  - Natural Resources Women's Platform, Committee on, 1973 (Box 6)
  - Oceanography Review Committee, 1977 (Box 6)
  - Program Chairmen Committee
    - Memoranda, 1974-1984 (Box 6)
      (includes some external correspondence)
    - Minutes (incomplete run), 1972-1984; 3 folders (Box 6)
  - Programs and Structure, Student/Faculty Committee on, 1969-1971 (Box 6)
  - Properties Committee, 2006 (Box 63)
  - Promotion and Tenure Review Committee, 1979 (Box 6)
  - Properties Board, 1975-1983 (Box 6)
  - Recruitment for Student Employment, Ad Hoc Committee on, 1970 (Box 6)
  - Reorganization Committee, 1968-1970 (Box 6)
  - Scholarship Committee, 1975-1981 (Box 6)
  - Space Committee, 1972-1981; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Special Events Task Force, 1977-1978 (Box 6)
  - Specialization Task Forces, 1983 (Box 6)
  - Student Grievance Procedure Committee, 1977-1978 (Box 6)
  - Student Policy Advisory Committee, 1971-1975 (Box 6)
  - Undergraduate Curriculum Committee, 1970-1982 (Box 6)
  - Undergraduate Program Committee
    - General, 1977-1981
    - Report, 1978 (Box 6)
  - Urban and Regional Planning, Committee on
    - Educational Objectives, 1966 (Box 6)
    - Minutes, 1966-1967 (Box 6)
  - Water Resources Committee
    - Correspondence, 1965-1976 (Box 6)
    - Minutes, 1969-1970 (Box 6)
    - Reports and News Release, 1965-1973 (Box 6)
  - Further Integration of Landscape Architecture in the School of Natural Resources, Task Group on, 1972 (Box 63)
  - Properties Committee, 2006 (Box 63)
- Conferences and Workshops, 1951-1983
  The folders in the Conferences and Workshops series (0.4 linear ft.) consist of planning and promotional materials from conferences and workshops that SNR sponsored or in which it participated during the years 1951 to 1983.
  - The Biological Significance of Environmental Impacts Workshop, 1975 (Box 7)
  - Council of Educators in Landscape Architecture, 1979 (Box 63)
    (Annual Meeting in Baton Rouge, Louisiana)
  - Educators Conference, 1977 (Box 7)
  - Freshwater Wetlands and Sewage Effluent Disposal: A Low-Cost Alternative to Tertiary Treatment, National Conference, 1976 (Box 7)
  - Great Lakes Shorelands Management Conference, 1974 (Box 7)
  - Impact Assessment in Water Resource Planning, Seminar on, 1973 (Box 7)
  - Legal Aspects of Wildlands Management, Conference of, 1977 (Box 7)
  - National Parks and Equivalent Reserves, International Seminar, 1965-1983 (Box 7)
  - National Summit on Coping with Climate Change, 2006-2007 (Box 63)
  - Reframing the Climate Change Debate: Jobs, Trade, Security, and a Revised Research Agenda, 2005 (Box 63)
  - Retrieval and Dissemination Workshop, 1976 (Box 7)
  - Science and Technology for Development, United Nations Conference, 1978 (Box 7)
  - Science and Technology for Management of Fragile Environments in Developing Nations, Conference of, 1978; 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Seminar '78, 1978 (Box 7)
  - Council of Educators in Landscape Architecture, 1979 (Box 63)
  - National Summit on Coping with Climate Change, 2006-2007 (Box 63)
  - Reframing the Climate Change Debate: Jobs, Trade, Security, and a Revised Research Agenda, 2005 (Box 63)
- Searches and Appointments, 1970-1990
  The Searches and Appointments series (.4 linear ft.), includes materials on a number of faculty and administrative searches between 1970 and 1990. Much of the material in this series contains assessments of the candidates and, therefore access to the files is restricted according to policy described in the Access and Use section.
  - General, 1975-1986 (Box 7)
  - Adjunct Appointments, 1987 (Box 51)
    [PR RESTRICTED until July 1, 2017 ]
  - Aquatic Entomology, 1978 (Box 7)
  - Conservation Biology, 1989-1990 (Box 51)
    [PR RESTRICTED until July 1, 2020 ]
  - "Dean's Interview Notes" (from various faculty searches), 1979 (Box 7)
  - Deanship Search Committee, 1974-1975 (Box 7)
  - Ecology, 1976-1980; 2 folders (Box 51)
    [PR RESTRICTED until July 1, 2080 ]
  - Environmental Communications, 1973-1977 (Box 51)
  - Fisheries, 1970-1972 (Box 51)
  - Fishery Management, 1977-1979 (Box 51)
  - Forest Management, 1976-1977 (Box 51)
  - Hydrology/Soils/Remote Sensing, 1973 (Box 51)
  - Natural Resource Economics, 1982-1984 (Box 51)
  - Natural Resource Management, 1976-1979
    - General (Box 51)
    - Candidates' Files, 3 folders (Box 51)
  - Natural Resource Policy and Administration, 1979-1980; 4 folders (Box 51)
  - Outdoor Recreation (Dana Chair)
    - 1974, 1977 (Box 51)
    - 1981 (Box 51)
  - Outreach, Student Services and Minority Affairs, Office of, Director Search (materials about), 1978 (Box 51)
  - Resource Policy and Management, 1976-1980; 3 folders (Box 51)
  - Soils/Watershed Hydrology, 1973 (Box 51)
  - Soils/Watershed Management
    - 1983-1984 (Box 51)
    - 1987 (Box 51)
  - Wetlands/Waterfowl Ecology, 1977 (Box 51)
  - Wildland Management Center, 1983-1984 (Box 51)
  - Wildlife, 1979-1980 (Box 51)
- Programs and Departments, 1939-1984
  The Programs and Departments series (3.2 linear ft.) includes records from 1939 to 1984 on SNR programs and departments. Types of materials found here include meeting minutes, committee reports, and correspondence and memoranda. Strongly documented are the Great Lakes and Marine Water Center and the Landscape Architecture Program. The Great Lakes and Marine Water Center is a university unit funded in part by SNR and in which SNR has administrative involvement. The Landscape Architecture Program is offered by SNR in conjunction with the College of Architecture and Urban Planning, and much of the material relates to the development of the program and its direction.
  - Behavior and Environment
    - Memoranda, 1975-83 (Box 7)
    - Reports, 1979-1982 (Box 7)
  - Biological Station
    - General, 1939-1954; 1974-1979 (Box 7)
    - Committee Reports, 1951-1954 (Box 7)
    - Executive Committee, 1951-1953; 1972; 1974 (Box 7)
    - Faculty Minutes, 1951-1954 (Box 7)
    - Paddock Report, 1978 (Box 7)
  - Botanical Gardens
    - Correspondence, 1966-1979 (Box 7)
    - Executive Committee, 1970-1974 (Box 7)
    - Radrick Bog and Forest, 1966-1967 (Box 7)
    - Survey, 1958-1963; 2 folders (Folder 1)
      (call no. UBImul/C241)
  - Camp Filibert Roth, 1978-1981 (Box 7)
  - Center for Sustainable Systems
    - Advisory Committee, 1998-2000 (Box 69)
    - Draft Business Plan, 2000 (Box 69)
    - Miscellaneous, 1997-2006 (Box 69)
    - Press Releases, 2002 (Box 69)
  - Corporate Environmental Management Program
    - Advisory Board, 1999-2001 (Box 69)
    - Miscellaneous, circa, 1995-2004 (Box 69)
    - Press Releases, 2002 (Box 69)
  - Environmental Justice Program, 1999-2001 (Box 70)
  - Degree Program for MidCareer Foresters, 1981 (Box 7)
  - Ecology, Fisheries and Wildlife Program, 1978-1980 (Box 8)
  - Ecosystem Management Initiative, 1998-2003 (Box 69)
  - Engineering Sustainable Systems Program, 2006 (Box 70)
    (Engineering/SNRE Dual Degree Program)
  - Environmental Simulation Laboratory (ESL)
    - General, 1970-1972 (Box 8)
    - Correspondence, 1969-1975; 3 folders (Box 8)
    - Gaming Service Center, 1972 (Box 8)
    - Report to Ford Foundation, 1970 (Box 8)
  - Environmental Justice Program, 1999-2001 (Box 70)
  - Erb Environmental Management Institute, 1999-2000 (Box 70)
  - Fish Program, 1977 (Box 8)
  - Fisheries, Forestry and Wildlife Program
    - Correspondence, 1965; 1972-1978 (Box 8)
    - Staff Meetings, 1973-1975 (Box 8)
  - Forest Resources Program, 1979-1984 (Box 8)
  - Forestry Department, 1969-1974 (Box 8)
  - Great Lakes and Marine Water Center
    - Aquatic Entomology, 1977-1978 (Box 8)
    - Great Lakes Program, 1974-1977 (Box 8)
    - Great Lakes Research Division
      - Correspondence, 1970-1974 (Box 8)
      - National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, 1973 (Box 8)
      - Presentations, 1972 (Box 8)
      - Program Development, 1972-1975 (Box 8)
    - National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, 1981 (Box 8)
    - Oceanography Review Committee Report, 1981 (Box 8)
    - Sea Grant Program
      - General, 1970-1978 (Box 8)
      - Budget Materials, 1969-1970 (Box 8)
      - Correspondence, 1970-1984; 6 folders (Box 8)
      - Grand Traverse Bay Project, undated (Box 8)
      - Policy Committee
        - General, 1968-1982; 4 folders (Box 8)
        - Minutes and Agendas, 1978-1981 (Box 8)
      - Program Advisory Committee, 1969-1972 (Box 9)
      - Proposals and Requests, 1970-1979 (Box 9)
      - Report to the University, 1972 (Box 9)
      - Resource Management Program, 1972 (Box 9)
      - Site Visit, 1978-1982 (Box 9)
      - Water Resources and Marine Science Program Committee, 1970 (Box 9)
  - Integrative Studies Center
    - General, 1978-1980 (Box 9)
    - Annual Reports with Executive Summary, 1979-1981 (Box 9)
    - Case Studies, 1978-1980 (Box 9)
    - Correspondence, 1978-1983 (Box 9)
    - Evaluation Project, Final Report, 1982 (Box 9)
    - Grants and Budgets, 1979-1982 (Box 9)
    - Steering Committee, 1978-1980 (Box 9)
  - Internship Program, circa, 2000 (Box 70)
  - Involvement of Black Students in the SNR, Ad Hoc Committee on, 1970 (Box 63)
  - Landscape Architecture
    - American Society of Landscape Architects
      - Accreditation Board, 1981; 2 folders (Box 9)
      - Evaluation Reports, 1976; 1981-1982; 2 folders (Box 9)
    - British Honduras Research, 1968 (Box 9)
    - College of Architecture and Design Enrollment Statistics and Trends, 1951-1964 (Box 9)
    - Correspondence, 1959-1974; 4 folders (Box 9)
    - Curriculum Review Committee, 1963-1964 (Box 9)
    - Faculty Meetings, 1962-1981 (scattered dates) (Box 10)
    - Michigan State Board of Landscape Architects, 1964-1967 (Box 10)
    - Michigan State Council for the Arts, 1966-1967 (Box 10)
    - Michigan Workshop
      - I, 1975 (Box 10)
      - II, 1977 (Box 10)
      - III, 1978 (Box 10)
    - Regional Planning, 1965-1968 (Box 10)
    - Report of Department Directions and Trends, 1967 (Box 10)
    - Study of Space Requirements, 1963 (Box 10)
  - Master of Regional Planning, 1973-1981 (Box 70)
  - Natural Resource Economics
    - Correspondence, 1967-1981; 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Reports, 1968-1975 (Box 10)
  - Natural Resources Organizational Management, 1990 (Box 70)
  - Natural Resource Policy and Law, 1976 (Box 10)
  - Ph.D. Program, 1978 (Box 10)
  - Ph.D. Program, 1982 (Box 70)
  - Remote Sensing
    - General, 1970-1976 (Box 10)
    - Correspondence, 1967-1975 (Box 10)
    - TERRA (Training in Earth Resources Remote-sensing Applications)
      - General, 1968-1971 (Box 10)
      - Curriculum Committee, 1968-1971 (Box 10)
    - UM/MSU Policy and Program Committee for Remote Sensing, 1970-1971 (Box 10)
  - Resource Ecology
    - General, 1970 (Box 10)
    - Correspondence, 1959-1979 (Box 10)
    - Faculty Minutes (incomplete run), 1971-1973 (Box 10)
  - Resource Planning and Conservation, 1968-1969 (Box 10)
  - Resource Policy and Management
    - General, 1974-1976 (Box 10)
    - Correspondence, 1973-1983 (Box 10)
    - Drake Paper, 1982 (Box 10)
    - Ecological Planning Proposal, 1973 (Box 10)
    - Faculty Minutes (incomplete runs), 1974-1977 (Box 10)
    - Faculty Vitas and Articles, undated (Box 10)
  - Student Planning Assistance to Community Environment (SPACE)
    - Bay City, 1979 (Box 70)
    - Cheboygan, 1980 (Box 70)
    - Gelman Sciences, 1982 (Box 70)
    - Huron River Corridor, 1984 (Box 70)
    - Miscellaneous, 1979-1980 (Box 70)
    - Muskegon, 1979-1981 (Box 70)
    - St. Clair, 1980 (Box 70)
    - Scio Township, 1980-1982 (Box 70)
      (includes slides)
  - Undergraduate Program, 1977-1980 (Box 10)
  - Urban and Regional Planning Program
    - General, 1978-1981 (Box 10)
    - Committee of Urban and Regional Planning, 1966 (Box 10)
    - Correspondence, 1967-1982 (Box 10)
    - Executive Committee, 1981-1982 (Box 10)
  - Urban, Technological and Environmental Planning (UTEP), 1982 (Box 10)
  - Wildlife and Fisheries, 1966-1969 (Box 10)
  - Wood Science and Technology Department, 1963-1964 (Box 10)
- School Reviews, 1967-1984
  The School Reviews series (3 linear ft.) is arranged chronologically by date of review and includes materials from school-wide reviews in 1967, 1970, 1976-1978, and 1982-1984. The majority of the series is comprised of materials from the 1982-1984 Review. The 1982-1984 Review was critical for SNR. It was initiated by the University's Budget Priorities Committee, which formed a Review Sub-Committee to evaluate SNR programs in terms of (1) quality and rigor, (2) cost and comparative productivity, and (3) importance or priority of the school in the university's overall mission. The sub-committee was further asked to determine whether the university should consider the discontinuance of SNR. The original arrangement of these materials as received from SNR has been retained, and consists of chronological folders, files of questions from the review committee, reports, and topical files. In response to the intense scrutiny SNR developed its own Development Plan Task Force and Transition Team in 1983 for the purposes of examining all functions of SNR, including curricula, faculty research and contributions, and SNR structure and governance.
  - Status Review-School of Natural Resources (report), 1967 (Box 11)
  - Natural Resources Review Committee, 1970
    - Communications (Box 11)
    - Reports (includes the Spurr Report) (Box 11)
    - Support Documents (Box 11)
  - 1976-1978 University Five Year Planning Program
    - Phase I (Box 11)
    - Phase II (Box 11)
    - Phase III (Box 11)
  - 1982-1984 Reviews, 1976-1982
    - Chronological Files
      - August 23, 1982 (Box 11)
      - August 24, 1982 (Box 11)
      - September 9, 1982 (Box 11)
      - September 16, 1982 (Box 11)
      - October 7, 1982, 2 folders (Box 11)
      - October 8, 1982 (Box 11)
    - Questions from the Review Committee